Richard A. Macias

4545 N GreenView Ave. Chicago, IL <u>Rmacias2454@gmail.com</u> <u>www.Richie-ee.com</u>

Software/Electrical Engineer

Professional Profile

Experience working as an Electrical Engineer and currently in school for a Masters in Computer Science. I've worked on various projects and tools in application development. The reason I enjoy Computer Science and Engineering is because it gives me the ability to make ideas come to life. I also really enjoy attending code and coffee groups.

Education

Master of Science in Computer Science, 2019 - Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA GPA: 3.75
Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering, 2014 - University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL GPA: 3.8
Spring 2018 Schedule: Graduate Operating Systems, Machine Learning, Machine Learning With Trading Classes Taken: Software Architecture, Database Systems, Software Design Process, Info Security.

Technical Skills

Languages: Java, C, HTML, CSS, Javascript, SQL, Python

Frameworks: Junit, Android, Picasso, Bootstrap,

Applications: Android Studio, Atom, Linux, Windows, GIT, IntelliJ IDEA

Self Taught in Object oriented Design, Data structures, and Algorithms.

Software Portfolio/Classwork Highlights

Full list of projects available on www.Richie-ee.com GitHub https://github.com/Rmacias91

Tool Rental Website (Fall 2017) Group Project

Website built from a 10+ page specification page on a Tool rental System for Database Systems Class.

Website was developed in stages. Report -> EER Mapping Diagram -> Website Implementation.

SQL for Schema, constraints per specs, and queries. HTML, JS, Jquery, and PHP for the website. Python and Bash to auto-populate database with dummy data for testing purposes.

Cryptogram Android Game (Summer 2017)

Android application created in a team of 4 in the Software Development Process class.

Tools used: Android Framework, TDD, Black Box Testing, UML class diagram, Documentation, Google Hangouts (Team Meetings), Agile Development.

Work Experience

Amped I LLC

Chicago, IL

Electrical Engineer

April 2015- April 2017

Worked under several teams of 2-5 engineers and for over 5 different clients. Upgraded 12kv Feeders, fiber communication, and digital fault recorders.

Helped start the drawing request intranet site using PHP, SQL, HTML, and CSS.

St. John's Optical Systems

Sanford, FL

Electrical Engineer Intern

Dec 2013- April 2015

Worked under senior Electrical Engineers and Physicists developing prototypes dealing with laser imaging and Infrared products.

Designed Printed Circuit boards, soldered, tested hardware and lasers.

University of Central Florida Orlando,FL

Research Assistant May 2013-Dec 2013

Aided graduate students in the research of Surface Acoustic Waves.